strongloop.com 2015-03-15

# StrongLoop | Privacy Policy

## StrongLoop Privacy Policy

### EFFECTIVE DATE: July 23, 2013

StrongLoop (“StrongLoop”) values your privacy. In this Privacy Policy (“Policy”), we describe how we collect, use, and disclose information that we obtain about visitors to our website, http://wwww.strongloop.com (the “Site”), and the services available through our Site (collectively, the “Services”). By visiting the Site, or using any of our Services, you agree that your personal information will be handled as described in this Policy. Your use of our Site or Services, and any dispute over privacy, is subject to this Policy and our Terms of Service, including its applicable limitations on damages and the resolution of disputes. Our Terms of Service are incorporated by reference into this Policy.

● What Information Do We Collect About You and Why?

● Information We Collect Directly From You

● Information We Collect Automatically

● How We Use Your Information

● How We Share Your Information

● Our Use of Cookies and Other Tracking Mechanisms

● Third Party Analytics

● Third-Party Links

● Security of My Personal Information

● Access To My Personal Information

● What Choices Do I Have Regarding Use of My Personal Information?

● Children Under 13

● Contact Us

● Changes to this Policy

### What Information Do We Collect About You and Why?

We collect information about you directly from you and from third parties, as well as automatically through your use of our Site or Services. Information We Collect Directly From You. Certain areas and features of our Site and Services, such as to access customer support and to participate in forums, require registration. To register with us, we collect your email address and user name. After you register with us, depending upon your use of our Services, you may have the option of creating a user profile. We will collect the information that you choose to provide in the profile, which may include, for example, your name, title, company name, and any other information that you provide to us. We also will collect any other information that you submit to us through your use of our Services, such as if you request information from us, submit content to our blogs, or otherwise interact with our Site and Services. Information We Collect Automatically. We automatically collect the following information about your use of our Site or Services through cookies, web beacons, and other technologies: your domain name; your browser type and operating system; web pages you view; links you click; your IP address; the length of time you visit our Site and or use our Services; and the referring URL, or the webpage that led you to our Site. We may combine the information this information with personal information that we have collected about you. Please see the section “What About Cookies and Other Tracking Mechanisms” below for more information. Information We Collect from Third Parties. If you choose to “Like” us, we receive your Facebook user ID, the pages you were visiting when you chose to “Like” us; we may also collect any profile information that you share with everyone. To review and manage the privacy settings for your Facebook account, including the information you share with everyone, you should refer to the privacy settings for your Facebook account and Facebook’s privacy policy – we have no control over what profile information is shared or made public by Facebook.

### How We Use Your Information

We use the information that we gather about you for the following purposes: To provide our Services to you, to communicate with you about your use of our Services, to respond to your inquiries, to fulfill your orders, and for other customer service purposes. To respond to technical questions. To tailor the content and information that we may send or display to you, to offer personalized help and instructions, and to otherwise personalize your experiences while using the Site or our Services. For marketing and promotional purposes. For example, we may use your information, such as your email address, to send you news and newsletters, special offers, and promotions, or to otherwise contact you about products or information we think may interest you. We also may use the information that we learn about you to assist us in advertising our Services on third party websites. To email you invitations to meetups and conferences that we believe would be of interest to you, including our own meetups and conferences as well as those hosted by third parties. To better understand how users access and use our Site and Services, both on an aggregated and individualized basis, in order to improve our Site and Services and respond to user desires and preferences, and for other research and analytical purposes. To administer our customer loyalty program.

### How We Share Your Information

We may share the information that we collect about you, including personally identifiable information, as follows: StrongLoop Users. Your user name and any information that you post to our Site, including, without limitation, reviews, comments, videos, and text will be available to, and searchable by, all users of the Site and Services. Business Partners. If we partner with another entity for the purposes of providing/offering a product or promotion, we may share your information with that other entity. Service Providers. We may disclose the information we collect from you to third party vendors, service providers, contractors or agents who perform functions on our behalf. Business Transfers. If we are acquired by or merged with another company, if substantially all of our assets are transferred to another company, or as part of a bankruptcy proceeding, we may transfer the information we have collected from you to the other company. In Response to Legal Process. We also may disclose the information we collect from you in order to comply with the law, a judicial proceeding, court order, or other legal process, such as in response to a court order or a subpoena. To Protect Us and Others. We also may disclose the information we collect from you where we believe it is necessary to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the safety of any person, violations of our Terms of Use or this Policy, or as evidence in litigation in which we are involved. Aggregate and De-Identified Information. We may share aggregate or de-identified information about users with third parties for marketing, advertising, research or similar purposes.

### Our Use of Cookies and Other Tracking Mechanisms

We use cookies and other tracking mechanisms to track information about your use of our Site or Services. We may combine this information with other personal information we collect from you. Cookies are alphanumeric identifiers that we transfer to your computer’s hard drive through your web browser for record-keeping purposes. Some cookies allow us to make it easier for you to navigate our Site and Services, while others are used to enable a faster log-in process or to allow us to track your activities at our Site and Service. There are two types of cookies: session and persistent cookies. Session Cookies. Session cookies exist only during an online session. They disappear from your computer when you close your browser or turn off your computer. We use session cookies to allow our systems to uniquely identify you during a session or while you are logged into the Site. This allows us to process your online transactions and requests and verify your identity, after you have logged in, as you move through our Site. Persistent Cookies. Persistent cookies remain on your computer after you have closed your browser or turned off your computer. We use persistent cookies to track aggregate and statistical information about user activity. Disabling Cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but if you prefer, you can edit your browser options to block them in the future. The Help portion of the toolbar on most browsers will tell you how to prevent your computer from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie, or how to disable cookies altogether. Visitors to our Site who disable cookies will be able to browse certain areas of the Site, but some features may not function. Local Storage Objects. We may use Flash Local Storage Objects (“Flash LSOs”) to store your Site preferences and to personalize your visit. Flash LSOs are different from browser cookies because of the amount and type of data stored. Typically, you cannot control, delete, or disable the acceptance of Flash LSOs through your web browser. For more information on Flash LSOs, or to learn how to manage your settings for Flash LSOs, go to the Adobe Flash Player Help Page, choose “Global Storage Settings Panel” and follow the instructions. To see the Flash LSOs currently on your computer, choose “Website Storage Settings Panel” and follow the instructions to review and, if you choose, to delete any specific Flash LSO. Clear GIFs, pixel tags and other technologies. Clear GIFs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on your computer’s hard drive, clear GIFs are embedded invisibly on web pages. We may use clear GIFs (a.k.a. web beacons, web bugs or pixel tags), in connection with our Site to, among other things, track the activities of Site visitors, help us manage content, and compile statistics about Site usage. We and our third party service providers also use clear GIFs in HTML e-mails to our customers, to help us track e-mail response rates, identify when our e-mails are viewed, and track whether our e-mails are forwarded. Third Party Analytics and Tracking. We use automated devices and applications, such as Google Analytics, to evaluate usage of our Site and, to the extent permitted, our Application. We also may use other analytic means to evaluate our Services. We use these tools to help us improve our Services, performance and user experiences. These entities may use cookies and other tracking technologies to perform their services. We do not share your personal information with these third parties.

### User Generated Content

We invite you to post content on our Site, such as posting to our blog or participating in our forums. You may submit comments, pictures, and videos (e.g., tutorials). Any content that you post to our Site will be available to all visitors to our Site. If you post your own content on our Site or Services, your posting may become public and we cannot prevent such information from being used in a manner that may violate this Policy, the law, or your personal privacy.

### Third-Party Links

Our Site and Services may contain links to third-party websites. Any access to and use of such linked websites is not governed by this Policy, but instead is governed by the privacy policies of those third party websites. We are not responsible for the information practices of such third party websites.

### Security of My Personal Information

We have implemented commercially reasonable precautions designed to protect the information we collect from loss, misuse, and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction. Please be aware that despite our best efforts, no data security measures can guarantee 100% security. You should take steps to protect against unauthorized access to your password, phone, and computer by, among other things, signing off after using a shared computer, choosing a robust password that nobody else knows or can easily guess, and keeping your log-in and password private. We are not responsible for any lost, stolen, or compromised passwords or for any activity on your account via unauthorized password activity.

### Access To My Personal Information

You may modify personal information that you have submitted by logging into your account and updating your profile information. Please note that copies of information that you have updated, modified or deleted may remain viewable in cached and archived pages of the Site for a period of time. What Choices Do I Have Regarding Use of My Personal Information? We may send periodic promotional emails to you. You may optout of such communications by following the opt-out instructions contained in the email. Please note that it may take up to 10 business days for us to process opt-out requests. If you opt-out of receiving emails about recommendations or other information we think may interest you, we may still send you e-mails about your account or any Services you have requested or received from us.

### Children Under 13

Our Services are not designed for children under 13. If we discover that a child under 13 has provided us with personal information, we will delete such information from our systems.

### Contact Us

If you have questions about the privacy aspects of our Services or would like to make a complaint, please contact us at callback@strongloop.com.

### Changes to this Policy

This Policy is current as of the Effective Date set forth above. We may change this Policy from time to time, so please be sure to check back periodically. We will post any changes to this Policy on our Site. If we make any changes to this Policy that materially affect our practices with regard to the personal information we have previously collected from you, we will endeavor to provide you with notice in advance of such change by highlighting the change on our Site, or by emailing users at the last registered address on record.
